Hello, you are watching Civil Business.
I hosted Aram Mkhitaryan, the group's
regional head for Central Asia and the Caucasus, and the
head of Yandex Armenia.  Hello.
Hello.   Thank
you, Aram, for accepting the invitation
.  Aram, just by introducing yourself, a
question arises, right?
We understand Yandex Armenia, we know that you
are the head of Yandex Armenia.  Then there was
information in the press a few months ago
that you were also appointed as the regional head of the Yango Group for
Central Asia and the Caucasus. Yango Group has
nothing to do with Yandex. Explain this connection a little bit.
Then let's move on. The group is a
very good one.
It is a large technology company with its
headquarters in
Dubai.
We work [in]
about 35 countries
around the world, if I'm not mistaken. We are talking
about the Asian markets of Latin America, Africa, and Asia, as well as about the Asian countries, with the
difference that if in the main
markets we work
using our main brand,
in the Asian countries we still continue to
work directly under the Yandex brand.
That is, the group uses the Yandex
brand in the CIS countries.
Yes, Yandex Armenia. Yandex Armenia
is part of the group
and provides the services that, by and large, are
offered by Yandex. I'm right,
not necessarily, because different
countries have their own
list of services, they differ significantly from each other,
and if we look at the two countries
About markets like I don't know Armenia and
Georgia, you can see that there are
certain services that
operate in Georgia, certain
services operate in Armenia, it
's clear, one of the main services is
always the locomotive taxi, so to speak
right-handing.
But
no, I mean it's
provided from the list of services that
Yandex has,
those technologies used the
technologies
that Yandex has, but
we have many services that were
originally created and appeared
exclusively in international markets.
For these specific markets, for example,
what service?
For example, we have the service
that originally started in the
Emirates, in the
United Arab Emirates it is a
service that is designed for [soul]
rental car aggregators
.  At the moment, it is available in the CIS countries
, if I'm not mistaken, in
Kazakhstan, and a week ago
we also launched it in Georgia.
Oh, very good, Aram.  The
volume of services that you provide to Armenia, first of all, before
moving on to that,
I can't help but ask about the relationship between the Group and Andex, let's clarify a little
and move on, yes the group
was created, I'll ask directly yes, so that
Yandex doesn't suddenly appear in
Yandex services that you provide in
other countries
outside of Russia yes, so that you avoid sanctions,
because you are a partner in appearing under sanctions,
or did this start earlier? I
think there are two thoughts that I
will express, which will put everything in its
place, so to speak. First, since it is a
Russian company, the
Andex company as such has never
been sanctioned,
and second, the group was created
well before 2022
and specifically to be presentable in international markets in a
different way.
And why was it not possible to be present with Yandex?
Look, the markets are very significantly different from
each other, starting from
how people pronounce the brand
name and how much they sew,
ending with the approaches, because we are
trying to see, there is one important thing  The
so-called home market
concept is
one thing,
but in new countries
we were first of all associated
with taxis, a high-
tech company, and we needed a brand with a new, more
youthful,
newer approach,
which was created in time, and that was long
before 22.
So, let me say that the ultimate beneficiary of the group is the
Russian parent company, I
mean where the income generated by the group is
ultimately accumulated,
where does the group go?
It is a company that has an
appropriate
structure. In the overall structure, there are
simple ones,
that is, it has shareholders, non-stakeholders,
shareholders who
are their shareholders.
As far as I know, not
shareholders, so I will say this so that we do